JOAO SANTOS

Web Developer

- @ dev.joaosantos@outlook.com @ linkedin.com/in/joaovitorps
- Ø github.com/joaovitorps
 Q Canoas, RS, Brazil

SUMMARY

4 years of experience as a programmer, where I learned a lot about how the web development process works. I have experience with the ReactJS library, the Bootstrap framework, GIT, Scrum, and the PHP programming language. Always looking to learn new languages and learn about new processes.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

02/2022 - Present

Scopic Software

Massachusetts, United States

- · Participate in daily scrums
- Check and work tickets from the user
- · Create hotfix for existing software products (React and PHP)

Lead Web Developer

02/2019 - 02/2022

Segure - Segurança do Trabalho

Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

- Implementation of new functionalities and maintenance in the company software
- Development of web applications with PHP (Codelgniter, Laravel), HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), and JavaScript (Angular, React)
- · MySQL database modeling
- · Team leadership
- · Agile scrum methodology

EDUCATION

Associate's in Computer Systems Analysis/Analyst

01/2018 - 12/2022

Universidade do Vale do Rio dos Sinos

TRAINING / COURSES

React

- Set up an application with Webpack
- Create components in React
- Integrate Redux into a React application
- · Develop an application from scratch with React Hooks and React/Redux
- Develop a full-stack application in Javascript
- Apply good development practices

Web Development

- NestJS + Strapi + PostgreSQL
- API REST with Node + Express + Sequelize
- Vue JS
- Socket IO
- GOF Design Patterns
- S.O.L.I.D Pinciples
- TDE
- Advanced Javascript + TypeScript
- Webpack e Babel

MongoDB - Beginner to Advanced

- CRUD with MongoDB
- Relationships between collections
- Database and collection management Create applications with Node, Express, and MongoDB / Mongoose
- MongoDB aggregation framework

LANGUAGES

English Proficient ••••

Portuguese Native ••••

SKILLS

React · JavaScript · Bootstrap · NodeJS ·

PHP · MongoDB · MySQL · GIT

Angular · Codelgniter · CSS · HTML ·

Github · Laravel · Scrum